<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Lane mayor the right honourable the lord mayor having a deep sense of the duty incumbent upon him ... for the suppression of prophaness [sic] and debauchery ...</title>
            <author>City of London (England). Lord Mayor.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 9KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 1 1-bit group-IV TIFF page image.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B26171</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">31354588</idno>
  <idno type="VID">205911</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2240857621</idno>
  
            <idno type="STC">Wing L2886R</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">31354588</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B26171)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 205911)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 1745:24)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Lane mayor the right honourable the lord mayor having a deep sense of the duty incumbent upon him ... for the suppression of prophaness [sic] and debauchery ...</title>
                  <author>City of London (England). Lord Mayor.</author>
                  <author>Lane, Thomas, Sir, 1652-1709.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.).   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed by Samuel Roycroft, Printer to the Honourable City of London,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London] :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1694.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>For enforcement of the laws governing Sunday activities.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in Guildhall Library (London, England).</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="topical_term">Sunday legislation --  England --  London.</term>
               <term type="geographic_name">London (England) --  History --  17th century.</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Broadsides --  London (England) --  17th century.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014-05 </date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-07 </date>
            <label>John Pas </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-07 </date>
            <label>John Pas</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="proclamation">
            <pb facs="tcp:205911:1"/>
            <head>
               <figure>
                  <figDesc>arms of London</figDesc>
               </figure> Lane Mayor.</head>
            <p>
               <seg rend="decorInit">T</seg>HE Right Honourable the LORD MAYOR having a deep Sense of the Duty incumbent upon him, as he is Intrusted with the Chief Magistracy of this CITY, to provide for the strict Observations of the Laws, and the Punishments of Offenders; and in a more especial manner, of such as shall be found offending against the Laws in force, for the suppression of Prophaness and Debauchery: And finding, that notwithstanding Their MAJESTIES Proclamations to enforce the Execution of those Laws, and the Care and Vigilance of several of his Lordship's Prede<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cessors, and of the <hi>Court of Aldermen,</hi> and other the Magistrates of this City, as well as his own Endeavours since his coming to the Chair, many grievous Vices and Enormities are still publickly committed, and go unpunished, to the great dishonour of Almighty GOD, and the Reproach and Scandal of this City, and the Government thereof.</p>
            <p>His Lordship being resolved to use all proper Methods for the more effectual remedying these Disorders, and (as far as in him lies) to procure a thorough Reformation of Manners in all places under his Jurisdiction, hath thought fit (with the Advice of his Brethren the <hi>Aldermen</hi>) to publish this ORDER; and doth strictly Charge and Require all Constables, Churchwardens, and Overseers of the Poor in their respective Parishes, and all other Officers and Ministers of Justice within this City and the Liberties thereof, as they tender the Honour of GOD, and the Welfare of this City; That they do in their several Stations apply themselves with all possible diligence to prevent the following Offences; and where that cannot be done, that they do what is in their power to bring the Offenders to condign Punishment.</p>
            <list>
               <label>(a) Prophanation of the LORD's-DAY by Sports and Pastimes.</label>
               <item>(a) Punishable by <hi>1 Car. 1.</hi> Penalty <hi>3 s. 4</hi> d. Conviction by one Witness, View of one Justice, or the parties Confession. Levied by distress, or in default Stocks three Hours.</item>
               <label>(b) Prophaness of the LORD's-DAY by Trades<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men, Artificers, Workmen, Labourers and others, Exercising the Works of their Ordinary Calling: Contrary to Law.</label>
               <item>(b) Punishable by <hi>29 Car. 2.</hi> Penalty <hi>5 s.</hi> Conviction by one Witness, view of Justice, or parties Confession. To be Levied by distress, or in default thereof, or in case of Insufficiency, the Offender to be set in the Stocks for two Hours.</item>
               <label>(c) By publick Crying, or Exposing to Sale, any Wares, Merchandizes, Fruits, or other Goods.</label>
               <item>(c) Punishable by the same Statute. Penalty, forfeiture of the Goods so Exposed or Cried, on the like Con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>viction.</item>
               <label>(d) By Travelling of Drovers, Horse-coursers, Higlers, and Others.</label>
               <item>(d) Punishable by the same Statute. Penalty, <hi>20 s.</hi> to be levied by distress, or in default the Stocks two Hours. Conviction by one Witness, &amp;c.</item>
               <label>(e) By any person Using or Employing any Wherry, Lighter, or Barge.</label>
               <item>(e) Punishable by the same Statute. Penalty <hi>5 s.</hi> levied by distress, or Stocks two Hours. Conviction by one Witness, Confession, or View of Justice.</item>
               <label>(f) By Idleing or Wandring in time of Divine Service.</label>
               <item>(f) Punishable by <hi>1 Eliz.</hi> Penalty <hi>12 d.</hi> to be levied by the Churchwardens by way of distress upon the Offender's Goods.</item>
               <label>(g) gBy continuing in Taverns, Ale-houses, and Coffee-houses, as well out of the time of Divine Service as in, contrary to the Laws in that Case provided.</label>
               <item>(g) Punishable by the several Statutes against Tipling in general, <hi>4 Jac. &amp; 21 Jac.</hi> Penalty <hi>3 s. 4 d.</hi> Conviction by one Witness, View of one Justice, or Confession of the Offender: Levied by distress, or the Stocks four Hours.</item>
               <label>(h) By Vintners, &amp;c. permitting Tipling in their Houses.</label>
               <item>(h) Punishable <hi>1 Jac. &amp; 1 Car. 1.</hi> Penalty <hi>10 s.</hi> Conviction by two Witnesses. In default of distress the Offender to be Committed to the Common Gaol till the Penalty paid.</item>
               <label>(i) Prophane Swearing and Cursing.</label>
               <item>(i) Punishable <hi>21 Jac.</hi> Penalty <hi>1 s.</hi> Conviction by two Witnesses; Hearing of one Justice or Confession. To be levied by distress; or if no distress can be had, to be set in the Stocks three Hours, if the Offender be above <hi>12</hi> year Old; else to be Whipt by the Constable, Parent or Master, in the presence of the Justice.</item>
               <label>(k) Drunkenness.</label>
               <item>(k) Punishable by <hi>4 &amp; 21 Jacobi.</hi> Penalty <hi>5 s.</hi> Conviction by one Witness, View, or Confession; to be levied by distress, or the Stocks for six Hours. For the second Offence, to be bound to the good Behaviour.</item>
               <label>(l) The keeping or frequenting Houses of Lewdness and Debauchery; or of Unlawful Games; and all other Irregular and Disorderly Practices, punishable by Law.</label>
               <item>(l) Such as keep Houses of Lewdness, Indictable and Finable, and to be bound to the Good Behaviour. Keepers of Gaming-houses, to enter into Recognizance, no longer to suffer such Gaming, <hi>33 Hen. 8.</hi> Resorters to such Houses, to be bound with Sureties no more to Play, by the same Statute.</item>
            </list>
            <p>And his Lordship doth hereby declare, That in case the aforesaid Officers, or any of them, shall in contempt of the Oaths they are under, refuse or neglect to do their Duty in the Premisses, or shall by partiality, connivance, giving private Notice to Offenders, or any other under-hand Practices, prevent their Discovery or Conviction, the Penalties appointed by the several Laws and Statutes shall be inflicted on them with the utmost Severity.</p>
            <p>And for the more effectual Suppressing the Vices afore-mentioned by a general and impartial Punishing of Offenders, His Lordship doth further recommend it to all good Citizens of this City, and others who shall at any time hereafter have knowledge of the Commission of any such Offences, or of the neglect or undue Practices of any Officer, to give timely Notice thereof to his Lordship, or some other of Their MAJESTIES Justices of the Peace within this City; His Lordship being resolved to take care, that all due Encouragement shall be given to such as shall so Inform; and that none shall be suffered to molest or disturb them in their giving Legal Information.</p>
            <p>And his Lordship doth likewise hereby Order, That all Constables, Churchwardens, and other Officers in their several Wards and Parishes, do from time to time, every Month, beginning from the 21th Day of <hi>December,</hi> 1694. bring and deliver to the <hi>Aldermen</hi> of their respective Wards, a true and perfect Account in Writing of all the Offenders by any of them Discovered or Charged, Prosecuted or Convicted, and their several Offences and the Penalties thereupon levied, and how the same are disposed of; To the end the said <hi>Alderman</hi> may bring the same before the COURT of <hi>Lord Mayor</hi> and <hi>Aldermen.</hi> And to that intent, all and every the <hi>Aldermen</hi> of the respective Wards are hereby desired and required, to Summon together once every Month all and every the Officers of their several Wards personally to receive from them an Account of their Proceedings concerning the premisses.</p>
            <p>And, that no Constable, or other Officer may be any ways Discouraged in the lawful, diligent, and vigorous Prosecution of his Duty in the premisses, His Lordship doth further declare, That if they, or any of them shall be resisted, vexed, or molested in the Execution of their Offices, they shall be vindicated by the Authority of the COURT of <hi>Lord Mayor</hi> and <hi>Aldermen,</hi> and the Offenders prosecuted and punished according to Law.</p>
            <closer>
               <signed>Goodfellow.</signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>Printed by <hi>SAMƲEL ROYCROFT,</hi> Printer to the Honourable City of <hi>LONDON,</hi> 1694.</p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>